Joseph Sciorra collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 4. Fieldwork and research about New York City neighborhoods, ca. 1981-2017
  - Williamsburg Pentecostal church, 2014, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 40/9)
  - Williamsburg People & Places (a Community Works publication), 2000, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 40/10)
  - You Tuan, undated, AFC 2018/065: PH059; 51 slides, color (35mm) (Box 56)
- Series 5. Administration, meetings, and professional pursuits, ca. 1979-2004
  Administrative materials surrounding the Calandra Italian American Institute, including monthly reports, programming, and meeting minutes. Also includes other materials related to Sciorra's career.
  - American Immigrant Autobiographies, ca. 1988, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 40/11)
  - American Studies Association presentation, 2008, afc2018065_dc074; 1 document file (PPT), 15 audio files (MP3)
  - Cabrini College, visiting scholar, 2004, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 40/12)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute Annual Report for Academic and Cultural Programs, 2001-2002, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 40/13)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute finances, April 2001, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 40/14)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute finances, June 2001, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 40/15)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute finances, July 2001, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 40/16)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute finances, August 2001, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 40/17)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute finances, September 2001, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/1)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute finances, October 2001, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/2)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute finances, November 2001, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/3)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute finances, December 2001, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/4)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute finances, February 2002, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/5)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute finances, April 2002, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/6)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute Monthly Report, January 2002, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/7)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute Monthly Report, February-March 2002, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/8)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute Monthly Report, May 2002, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/9)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute Monthly Report, July 2002, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/10)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute Monthly Report, August 2002, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/11)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute Monthly Report, September 2002, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/12)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute Monthly Report, January 2003, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/13)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute Monthly Report, February 2003, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/14)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute Monthly Report, March 2003, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/15)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute Monthly Report, April 2003, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/16)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute Monthly Report, May 2003, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/17)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute programming, October 2003, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/18)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute programming, November 2003, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/19)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute programming, 2002-2003, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/20)
  - Calandra Italian American Institute weekly minutes, 2003, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/21)
  - "Communities and the Humanities" meeting, 2001, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/22)
  - Conferences/lecture series about Italian Americans, 2005, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/23)
  - Cooperative Recreation Service custom publications, 1/3, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 41/24)
  - Cooperative Recreation Service custom publications, 2/3, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/1)
  - Cooperative Recreation Service custom publications, 3/3, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/2)
  - Correspondence for Calandra Italian American Institute, 2001, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/3)
  - Correspondence for Calandra Italian American Institute, 2002, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/4)
  - Follow up memos, Calandra Italian American Institute, 2002, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/5)
  - Immigrant communities: Article about Social Clubs, 1999, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/6)
  - Joe Sciorra meetings weekly minutes, 2000, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/7)
  - Joe Sciorra meetings weekly minutes, 2001, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/8)
  - Joe Sciorra meetings weekly minutes, 2002, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/9)
  - Joe Sciorra's memos, Calandra Italian American Institute, 2000, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/10)
  - Legislative grant: Calandra Italian American Institute, Queens, 2000-2002, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/11)
  - Malidittu la Lingua 1990, Vincenzo Ancona, Anna L. Chairetakis, Joseph Sciorra; 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 44/16)
  - Malidittu la Lingua audiobook part 1, 1990, afc2018065_dc049; Vincenzo Ancona, Anna L. Chairetakis, Joseph Sciorra; 13 audio files (WAV)
  - Malidittu la Lingua audiobook part 2, 1990, afc2018065_dc050; Vincenzo Ancona, Anna L. Chairetakis, Joseph Sciorra; 26 audio files (WAV)
  - Mediterranean Studies Association conference, 2005, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/12)
  - Mithra cult/religion, 1989-2006, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/13)
  - Navajo sandpainting essay, 1979, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/14)
  - NYU graduate financial aid awards, 1982-1985, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/15)
  - Objects/storytelling, 1988-2003, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/16)
  - Papers by and about Joseph Sciorra, 2003-2004, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/17)
  - PhD applications, 1986-1996, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/18)
- Series 6. Italy and Italian American communities research, ca. 1983-2014
  Research and documentation of Italian and Italian American traditions.
  - Alfred Polizotto death notice, 2001, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/19)
  - Banner/emblem exhibit, 2003, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/20)
  - Banners, 1999-2003, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 42/21)
  - Bocce notes, etc., 1981, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/1)
  - Brigandage/Southern Italy, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/2)
  - Castellamare del Golfo, ca. 1991, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/3)
  - Castellamare del Golfo, ca. 1991, AFC 2018/065: PH029; 2 slides, color (35mm) (Box 50)
  - Castellemmarese mafia, 2003-2007, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/4)
  - Castrofillipo images, 1986, AFC 2018/065: PH080; 11 slides, color (35mm) (Box 50)
  - Castrofillipo select images, 1986, AFC 2018/065: PH081; 37 slides, color (35mm)
  - Catholicism and Mafia, 2007-2013, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/5)
  - Costume making images, 1986, AFC 2018/065: PH079; 7 slides, color (35mm) (Box 59)
  - Gangs, ca. 2012-2015, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/6)
  - (Gay/Lesbians in Catholicism): De Bernardo-Bondings (newspaper periodical), 1999-2000, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/7)
  - Gardens images, 1986, AFC 2018/065: PH078; 7 slides, color (35mm) (Box 59)
  - Good Friday images, 1986, AFC 2018/065: PH074; 14 slides, color (35 mm) (Box 59)
  - Italian American Christmas article in New Jersey Performing Arts Center publication, 1997, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/8)
  - Italian American folklore bibliography, 1988-1989, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/9)
  - Italian American movie review, 1983-1991, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/10)
  - Italian American organizations, ca. 1996, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/11)
  - Italian American place and food traditions, 2000-2001, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/12)
  - Italian American style, 2010-2013, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/13)
  - Italian Catholics, 1/2, 1986-2014, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/14)
  - Italian Catholics, 2/2, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/15)
  - Italian Folklore Studies bibliography, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/16)
  - (Italian) migration research, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/17)
  - Italian soccer, Brooklyn, 1986-1988, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/18)
  - Italians in Newark, ca. 1988, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/19)
  - Italians in Newark, ca. 1988, AFC 2018/065: PH030; 25 slides, color (Box 50)
  - Italians in Newark, ca. 1988, AFC 2018/065: PH100; 5 film negatives, color (35mm) (Box 62)
  - Lou Nasti, 2005-2012, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/20)
  - Luisa del Giudice - Italian American folklore book, 1992-1995, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/21)
  - Maria SS. Della Civita Itri Club dinner dance program, 1990, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/22)
  - Mobster: Angelo Spata, 2013-2014, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/23)
  - Mt. Carmel research, ca. 1980-2006, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/24)
  - National Italian American Foundation (NIAF), Anti-Defamation, 2001-2004, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/25)
  - Nicknames, ca. 1984-1990, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 45/6)
  - Nicknames article, 1988, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 43/26)
  - Organized crime, 1987-2010, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 44/1)
  - Our Lady of Mt. Carmel Fraternal Society, 1986-2003, AFC 2018/065: PH048; 30 slides, color (35mm) (Box 54)
  - Painting images, 1986, AFC 2018/065: PH076; 4 slides, color (35mm) (Box 59)
  - Pasquale Turrigiano, 2004, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 44/2)
  - Photography prints from Anna Chairetakis, 1986, 15 prints, color (4x5) (Box-folder 44/3)
  - Preserves and Italian wine images, AFC 2018/065: PH077; 2 slides, color (35mm) (Box 59)
  - "Processing slides," ca. 1986, AFC 2018/065: PH043; 33 slides, color (35mm) (Box 53)
  - Religion and Spirituality in Italian American Life (symposium), 2000, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 44/4)
  - Research about Nola, Italy (in Italian), 1981-1985, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 44/5)
  - Sala Consilina, Italy, 2001-2006, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 44/6)
  - San Cono di Teggiano Catholic Association Ladies' Auxiliary, 2002, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 44/7)
  - San Cono di Teggiano Catholic Association, Brooklyn, NY, 1997, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 44/8)
  - San Cono: Interpretacion de los Suenos (book), undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 44/9)
  - San Cono: Mons. Amabile Federico (book), 1971, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 44/10)
  - Scemo di Guerra magazine, 1991, 1 folder of manuscripts, legal (Box-folder 46/9)
  - Social club images, 1986, AFC 2018/065: PH075; 4 slides, color (35mm) (Box 59)
  - Solenne Incoronazione della Immagine Miracolosa di Maria SS. del Carmine in New York (book), 1904, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 44/11)
  - Southern Italian anti-Clericalism, 2007, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 44/12)
  - Susan Baldwin photographs of wine making, ca. 1986, 43 photographic prints, color (4x5) (Box-folder 44/13)
  - Unidentified photographs of costumed event, ca. 1985-1987, 12 photographic prints, color (4x6) (Box-folder 44/14)
  - Upstate Italians exhibit, ca. 1987-1993, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 44/15)
  - Wine making images, ca. 1986, AFC 2018/065: PH070; 23 slides, color (35mm) (Box 59)
  - Wine making select images, ca. 1986, AFC 2018/065: PH071; 14 slides, color (35mm) (Box 59)
  - Optical media, Optical discs that contained the digital files found in this collection.; 71 optical discs (CD-R, DVD-R) (Box 49-50)